<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<articles>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.9</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-06-17">2015-06-17</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Add ability to retrieve HTTP headers from the request.
				This adds several fields to the structure filled in by <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a> that allow for mapped
				(indexed by known header) and listed header fields.
				The HTTP headers are reconstituted from the CGI environmental variables according to the RFC.
				These fields existed in earlier releases, but were not documented and, moreover, did not reconstitute the HTTP header name from
				the CGI environment variable name.
				A regression test has been added to test this behaviour.
				While adding this documentation, clean up the type list in <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a>.
			</div>
			<div>
				Add <a href="khttp_body.3.html">khttp_body_compress(3)</a>, which allows for stipulating auto-compression (the default for
				<a href="khttp_body.3.html">khttp_body(3)</a>), compression without emitting the appropriate header (for applications
				providing the <q>Content-Encoding</q> parameter themselves), and no compression (for applications taking full control of
				output themselves).
				While there, make the test for requested compression be sensitive to the <a
					href="http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec14.html">RFC 2616</a> <q>qvalue</q>.
				Both functions now return whether compression has been enabled.
				This functionality augments existing behaviour: it does not change it.
			</div>
			<div>
				Add HTTP error codes described by <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6585">RFC 6585</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.4.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2014-11-30">2014-11-30</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Implement the <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a> library for convenient JSON functions, remove function prototype names
				as per OpenBSD's <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man9/style.9?query=style">style(9)</a>, polish
				documentation.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.4.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2014-12-03">2014-12-03</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Make sure that <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a> returns an error code indicating what actually went wrong.
				This is a minor API change because the function no longer returns 0, but an enumeration (where 0, incidentally, means success).
				Also audit the parsing trailer to make sure that the parent doesn't exit in the event of memory exhaustion.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.4.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2014-12-15">2014-12-15</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Add the Boolean and NULL types to <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a>.
				Fix control code serialisation in the same.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2014-12-18">2014-12-18</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Expand the functionality of the template system with <a href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_templatex(3)</a> and <a
					href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_templatex_buf(3)</a>, which allow the writing function to be overriden.
				This allows templates to play nicely with other systems such as <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a> and general dynamic
				buffer creation.
				I use this for creating mails for sending with <a href="http://curl.haxx.se/libcurl/">libcurl</a>.
				Also create an automated test harness <a href="kcgi_regress.3.html">kcgi_regress(3)</a> that, for internal automated regression
				testing, uses <a href="http://curl.haxx.se/libcurl/">libcurl</a> to create and parse HTTP messages over a local socket and a
				small server to translate the requests into CGI variables for <span class="nm">kcgi</span>.
				The internal tests can be run with <code>make regress</code>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-03-14">2015-03-14</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Allow <a href="kcgi_regress.3.html">kcgi_regress(3)</a> to handle query strings and forms for validation testing.
				Pick out one assertion failure in the parser by using the <a href="http://lcamtuf.coredump.cx/afl/">American fuzzy lop</a>.
				Add an a test harness for AFL as well.
				Recognise CONNECT, DELETE, HEAD, TRACE, PUT, and OPTIONS methods.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-05">2015-04-05</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Allow for opaque HTTP message bodies: if our content type isn't <code>application/x-www-form-urlencoded</code>,
				<code>multipart/form-data</code>, or <code>text/plain</code> (during a POST only), then accept the HTTP body as a single object
				and validate it against the empty-key validator.
				Add HTTP methods and headers stipulated by <a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4918">HTTP Extensions for Web Distributed
					Authoring and Versioning (WebDAV)</a> and <a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4791">Calendaring Extensions to WebDAV
					(CalDAV)</a>.
				Allow for the HTTP request headers to be exported to the <code>struct kreq</code> object as both a list and, for common
				HTTP headers, an indexed map.
				Added <a href="kcgixml.3.html">kcgixml(3)</a> bits for some simple XML support and added <code>khtml_putc()</code> and
				<code>khtml_puts()</code> to <a href="kcgihtml.3.html">kcgihtml(3)</a> for consistency.
				Specify that a <code>NULL</code> template passed to the <a href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_template(3)</a> functions simply
				causes the named file or buffer to be outputted without any processing.
				Lastly, recognise <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man2/getentropy.2">getentropy(2)</a> as a
				white-listed system call in the <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man4/systrace.4">systrace(4)</a>
				sandbox.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-10">2015-04-10</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fully process the <code>Authentication</code> header, implementing <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2617">RFC 2617</a>.
				This was originally developed in <a href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcaldav">kcaldav</a>, but makes more sense to be run here
				inside of the untrusted child.
				Values are stored in the <code>struct khttpauth</code> field documented in <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-12">2015-04-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Single bug-fix: the nonce count parsed from an HTTP digest was not being correctly recorded.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-12">2015-04-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Bug-fix when linking to <a href="kcgihtml.3.html">kcgihtml(3)</a>.
				Added the access scheme (HTTP or HTTPS) to <code>struct kreq</code>.
				Have validation for document body correctly set the <code>ctypepos</code> prior to validation.
				While there, properly decode the content-type field (i.e., discarding parameters) when looking up the type in the known types.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-23">2015-04-23</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Bug-fix for Capsicum sandbox, found by Baptiste Daroussin.  (Thanks!)
				Also fix passing a zero-length buffer into the template buffer functions.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.7</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-04-27">2015-04-27</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Rename <code>khtml_close</code> to <code>khtml_closeelem</code> in <a href="kcgihtml.3.html">kcgihtml(3)</a>, then re-add the
				close function and an open function to harmonise with <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a> and <a
					href="kcgixml.3.html">kcgixml(3)</a>.
				In the process, allow the closing functions in all libraries to unwind any remaining context, and have the closing functions
				return whether the request was out of bounds.
				Prevent some bogus calls to <a href="kcgihtml.3.html">kcgihtml(3)</a> from aborting.
				Bug-fix for detecting zlib on FreeBSD, found by Baptiste Daroussin.  (Thanks!)
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.5.8</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-05-11">2015-05-11</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Update the included sample file and correct the documentation regarding its compilation.
				Fix noted by Jan Schreiber &#8212; thanks!
				While doing so, add some documentation bits to the manpages and considerable documentation to the webpage.
				No functional changes.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-07-07">2015-07-07</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Import initial Linux <a href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/seccomp.2.html">seccomp(2)</a> (via <a
					href="http://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man2/prctl.2.html">prctl(2)</a>) sandbox!
				This uses the implementation of <a href="http://www.openssh.com/">OpenSSH</a>, tweaked to work within the <span
					class="nm">kcgi</span> framework.
				For now, it only allows arm, i386, and x86_64: if you're using another architecture, please let me know your <code>uname -m</code>, 
				as the sandbox (ridiculously) needs to know the system architecture.
				(Better yet: also send me the relevant <code>AUDIT_ARCH_xxx</code> from <code>/usr/include/linux/audit.h</code>.)
				While here, allow for compilation on <a href="http://www.musl-libc.org/">musl</a>.
				I've also moved the tutorial into a separate file and fleshed it out a little.
				I'll probably add more tutorials in time.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.6.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-07-09">2015-07-09</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				One-line bug-fix to include new Linux seccomp patch into source archive.  Ouch.  Noted by James Turner&#8212;thanks!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>

	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.6.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-07-18">2015-07-18</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				More FastCGI: move control socket handling into its own process.
				The control socket is a UNIX socket (or similar) bound by the FastCGI runner, which is either the web server or an
				application like <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>, then passed as <code>STDIN_FILENO</code> to the FastCGI
				application.
				<span class="nm">kcgi</span> will then wait on this socket for incoming connections, which are acted upon with <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_parse.3.html">khttp_fcgi_parse(3)</a>.
				In this release, this logic has been moved into its own process instead of being managed by the web application itself
				during calls to <a href="khttp_fcgi_parse.3.html">khttp_fcgi_parse(3)</a>.
				While here, I cleaned up and simplified a lot of the sandbox and inter-process socket logic.
				The control socket is not yet sandboxed: that will come with later releases.
				Again, the FastCGI implementation is <strong>experimental</strong>!
			</div>
			<div>
				Patches for deployment on FreeBSD contributed by Baptiste Daroussin&#8212;thanks!
				In analysis, found that the <code>argfree</code> function to <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a> wasn't
				being invoked if the <code>arg</code> was itself NULL.
				(This is clearly bad behaviour&#8212;not all functions need that argument!)
				This has been fixed as well.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>

	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.6.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-07-15">2015-07-15</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				This release includes an initial implementation of <a href="http://www.fastcgi.com">FastCGI</a>.
				While the existing functionality wasn't logically altered, it was shuffled around quite a lot and abstracted to
				accomodate for the new FastCGI functions.
				The implementation is documented in <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>, <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_init.3.html">khttp_fcgi_init(3)</a>, and <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_parse.3.html">khttp_fcgi_parse(3)</a>, and <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_free.3.html">khttp_fcgi_free(3)</a>.
				<strong>This functionality is experimental</strong>, and needs strong analysis before casual deployment.
				It is also not quite feature-complete: HTTP compression is not yet functional for FastCGI applications.
				The <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a> launcher is also very bare-bones&#8212;this will be improved in subsequent releases.
				Again: this functionality is <strong>experimental</strong> and under development!
			</div>
			<div>
				Also fixed a bug where calling <a href="khttp_free.3.html">khttp_free(3)</a> after a prior <a
					href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a> failure would cause a NULL dereference.
				Added the missing <code>txt</code> and <code>xml</code> suffixes to the suffix table.
				Fix that the request port number was erroneously disallowed to be &gt;80.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.6.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-08-01">2015-08-01</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Add some proper security to <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>: place child FastCGI processes in a file-system jail,
				drop privileges, and ensure proper ownership of the socket.
				While here, begin sandbox mechanisms for the FastCGI control process.
				This only works for Mac OSX for now, but will expand to others.
				Again, until the next minor version bump, <strong>FastCGI support is experimental</strong>.
			</div>
			<div>
				On that note, finalise the API for FastCGI calls.
				This involved moving most function arguments previously in <a href="khttp_fcgi_parse.3.html">khttp_fcgi_parse(3)</a>
				into <a href="khttp_fcgi_init.3.html">khttp_fcgi_init(3)</a>.
				To wit, the <code>khttp_fcgi_parsex()</code> function has been removed: all of the logic has been moved to the
				initialisation function, making the parse function much simpler.
				Cement this by adding several new regression tests that exercise the FastCGI functionality.
				These, of course, required that FastCGI functionality be added to the regression suite.
				This is documented in <a href="kcgiregress.3.html">kcgiregress(3)</a> (the manpage was renamed from <code>kcgi_regress</code>).
			</div>
			<div>
				In adding the regression suite, one critical FastCGI bug was found (and fixed) for forms &gt;1 kB.
				Fix another critical bug when writing large contiguous blocks, which would be silently truncated.
				(A regression test has been added for this.)
				The same would trigger a failure on Linux due to the sandbox: this has also been fixed.
				Internally, the behaviour of read and write sockets is consistently non-blocking.
				There has been a report of large compressed output failing on FreeBSD, but this has not yet been verified.
			</div>
			<div>
				Lastly, incorporate a patch from Baptiste Daroussin (thanks!) for a tighter Capsicum sandbox for the parser process.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.0</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-08-07">2015-08-07</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Implement the <a href="http://www.fastcgi.com/drupal/node/6?q=node/22">FastCGI</a> control process's sandbox for all
				supported operating systems.
				(The FastCGI control process is forked from each application process, and is responsible for accepting new FastCGI
				connections and passing the descriptors to the application for output and worker process for parsing.)
				This is the last <q>feature</q> for the FastCGI implementation: it now has the same protection as the CGI implementation
				for all child processes.
				Add sandbox for OpenBSD's <a href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man2/tame.2">tame(2)</a>,
				although this technically isn't supported yet (in snapshots, anyway) and returns <code>ENOSYS</code>.
				On OpenBSD machines with both sandboxes, this is tried first.
				This effort derives from a patch submitted by Reyk Floeter&#8212;thanks!
			</div>
			<div>
				The FastCGI interface is no longer an experimental feature, but baked into the system.
			</div>
			<div>
				In addition to the above, some variables were added to the manpages (which were also cleaned up a bit) and the AFL
				system was updated with the socket re-write.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-08-11">2015-08-11</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fix: forgot to install <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>.
				Add flag to <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a> to specify the connection backlog.
				Add <a href="khttp_fcgi_test.3.html">khttp_fcgi_test(3)</a> to see if an application should use the FastCGI or regular
				CGI functions.
				A regression noted by James Turner (thanks!): re-add the CGI sample, <span class="file">sample.c</span>, into the
				distributed source.
				There is also a FastCGI sample, <span class="file">sample-fcgi.c</span>.
				There is also a non-<span class="nm">kcgi</span> sample, <span class="file">sample-cgi.c</span>, used in creating the
				performance graphs.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-09-04">2015-09-04</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				If a FastCGI connection closes, don't make
				failing writes to that connection bring down the
				application.
				Also work around a very weird Mac OS X bug
				wherein a poll will return a timeout even though
				the poll request is blocking.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-09-30">2015-09-30</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fix for proper FastCGI support on <a href="http://www.nginx.org">nginx</a>.
				This work was prompted by Daniel Sinclair, who fixed a read type mismatch (when reading the padding length) that inspired
				a further fix to serialise the response FastCGI header properly.
				Lastly, a latent Apache2 FastCGI bug was fixed in incorrectly reporting the return code status.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2015-11-12">2015-11-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Replace support for tame(2) (which was never enabled in the operating system) with the renamed <a
					href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man2/pledge.2">pledge(2)</a>.
				From a patch by James Turner&#8212;thank you!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-01-04">2016-01-04</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Added ability to easily perform HTTP digest authentication, <a
					href="khttpdigest_validate.3.html">khttpdigest_validate(3)</a>, which is heavily used in <a
					href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcaldav">kcaldav</a> and a few other systems.
				This manages all of the aspects of the sequences, from the child process performing an MD5 hash on the full data stream
				to the end check against a hash.
				While there, also add <a href="khttpbasic_validate.3.html">khttpbasic_validate(3)</a> for completeness.
			</div>
			<div>
				Add an experimental feature for debugging input and output streams.
				One can set debugging fields with <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parsex(3)</a> or <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_init.3.html">khttp_fcgi_initx(3)</a> and have request reads or response writes logged to
				standard output.
				<strong>Note</strong>: this changes the system API, so make sure any systems calling the above functions are upgraded to
				account for the extra argument!
				Also merged a thorough documentation patch by Svyatoslav Mishyn&#8212;thanks!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-01-25">2016-01-25</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Push read-only repository to <a href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcgi.git">GitHub</a>.
				<span class="nm">kcgi</span> has been accepted as a <a href="https://scan.coverity.com/projects/kcgi">Coverity</a>
				project.
				The initial scan revealed a pair of error-path resource links and some false positives.
				(All of these are visible on the Coverity project site.)
				It also found one legitimate bug in the newly-installed HTTP basic authentication code.
				This, obviously, has been fixed.
				Thanks, <a href="http://coverity.com">Coverity</a>!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.7</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-02-10">2016-02-10</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Allow for the developer to set a write buffer size when invoking <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parsex(3)</a> or <a
					href="khttp_fcgi_init.3.html">khttp_fcgi_initx(3)</a>.
				The write buffer hooks into <a href="khttp_write.3.html">khttp_write(3)</a> and, if set to a non-zero size, will cause
				writes to be buffered.
				This changes existing behaviour where writes were never buffered.
				Note that this function is invoked by all writing functions, both within <a href="kcgi.3.html">kcgi(3)</a> and its
				libraries such as <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a>.
				The buffer is flushed when its size is exceeded or when <a href="khttp_free.3.html">khttp_free(3)</a> is invoked.
				If not provided, the default is 8 KiB for CGI and 65 KiB for FastCGI.
				Also renamed the <code>xmalloc</code>-style internal functions so as not to override weak symbols in any interfacing
				applications.
				This was noted by Okan Demirmen&#8212;thanks!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.7.8</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-03-02">2016-03-02</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Use <a
					href="http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi/OpenBSD-current/man3/strtonum.3">strtonum(3)</a> whenever possible,
				inspired by a patch from Jan Schreiber&#8212;thanks!
				Add <a href="khttpdigest_validate.3.html">khttpdigest_validatehash(3)</a>, which authenticates an HTTP digest session using a pre-computed hash.
				(The existing function builds the hash from a password.)
				This is required by <a href="http://kristaps.bsd.lv/kcaldav">kCalDAV</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.8.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-03-15">2016-03-15</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Significantly update the FastCGI handling.
				There were two foci to this effort:
				first, to make the existing FastCGI
				system more robust in terms of starting
				and stopping; the second, to extend
				FastCGI so that <a
					href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>
				can handle variable-sized pools of
				workers instead of a fixed number.
				The method of extending FastCGI is
				described in <a
					href="extending01.html">FastCGI
					Extensions for Management
					Control</a>, and is implemented
				by the -<span class="flag">r</span> flag
				in <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.8.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-04-06">2016-04-06</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fix the -<span class="flag">l</span> flag in <a href="kfcgi.8.html">kfcgi(8)</a> as dictated in <a
					href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcgi/pull/1">pull/1</a> on the <a
					href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcgi">GitHub</a>.
				Thanks, <a href="https://github.com/cornett">cornett</a>!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.8.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-04-19">2016-04-19</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Work around an <a href="https://marc.info/?l=openbsd-tech&amp;m=144571751203238&amp;w=2">old but fatal FastCGI
					problem</a> only found on OpenBSD's <a href="https://github.com/reyk/httpd">httpd</a>.
				This assumes that HTTP headers are only on the first FastCGI packet, which is not part of the standard.
				The workaround is to have HTTP headers buffer just like the HTTP body, which will cause multiple headers to lump
				into (hopefully) one packet.
				Headers are still flushed when the HTTP body begins, however, although I'm still unsure whether this is a good
				idea.
				(It pushes the status code to the web server faster, but incurs an extra trip on the wire.)
				If you've disabled buffering in <a href="khttp_fcgi_init.3.html">khttp_fcgi_init(3)</a>, or you have so many
				headers that the output buffer is flushed before the last header, <a
					href="https://github.com/reyk/httpd">httpd</a> will intermix your body with headers.
				Ew.
				This problem was raised as <a href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcgi/issues/2">issues/2</a> by <a
					href="https://github.com/cornett">@cornett</a>&#8212;thanks!
				Also fix <a href="https://github.com/kristapsdz/kcgi/issues/3">issues/3</a>, raised by the same&#8212;thanks
				again!
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.8.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-06-14">2016-06-14</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fix several documentation bugs that erroneously noted values can be NULL when they would instead by empty
				strings.
				Also fixed some broken links.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.8.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-08-19">2016-08-19</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Some documentation fixes and clarifications as suggested by Ross Richardson&#8212;thanks!
				Also added a <a href="tutorial3.html">custom validation tutorial</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.0</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-10-10">2016-10-10</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Regressions, regressions, regressions, regressions.
				Fix <a href="kcgiregress.3.html">kcgiregress(3)</a> to work in a more general fashion, adding an example usage
				along the way.
				Regression tests are (sadly) not used often for web applications, so this tool should be a welcome one!
				Also add two useful functions: <a href="kutil_epoch2str.3.html">kutil_epoch2str(3)</a> for converting from
				integral (epoch) UNIX time into an HTTP date and <a href="kutil_date2epoch.3.html">kutil_date2epoch(3)</a> and <a
					href="kutil_date2epoch.3.html">kutil_datetime2epoch(3)</a> for converting from dates to integral time.
				Lastly, clarify that <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a> requires a call to <a
					href="khttp_free.3.html">khttp_free(3)</a> if and only if it returns success.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.1</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-10-17">2016-10-17</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Get rid of BSD make in favour of <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/make/">GNU make</a>.
				I generally don't like GNU software, so let me explain: portability and readability.
				The original Makefile was almost 500 lines; the new one is 350.
				While this software isn't exactly a moving target, it's still annoying to add the same lines over and over
				again.
				If you can think of a better way, please let me know.
			</div>
			<div>
				Next, add some logging functions: <a href="kutil_log.3.html">kutil_log(3)</a> and friends.
				Why?
				I find myself re-rolling these same routines over and over again.
				They're similar (enough) to the NCSA format, sanitise (and bound) output, and time-stamp without tripping <a
					href="http://man.openbsd.org/pledge.2">pledge(2)</a>.
			</div>
			<div>
				Lastly, add an index of all <a href="functions.html">functions</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.2</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2016-11-27">2016-11-27</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Following a report by Ross Richardson (thanks!), fix cookie handling.
				Before, cookie values (and keys) were being handled as URL-encoded strings.
				Now they're correctly handled as opaque values; and moreover, they use a stricter check against <a
					href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6265">RFC 6265</a>.
				While there, update some spelling and typos (thanks Svyatoslav!).
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.3</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2017-01-25">2017-01-25</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Numerous spelling errors fixed (no functional change) and added <a
					href="kutil_epoch2str.3.html">kutil_epoch2utcstr(3)</a> for formatting ISO 8601 dates.
				Also fixed <a href="kutil_epoch2str.3.html">KUTIL_EPOCH2TM(3)</a> macro to set correct fields.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.4</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2017-03-12">2017-03-12</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Add a feature inspired by Ross Richardson: a fallback function for templates.
				As described for the <a href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_template(3)</a> family of functions, 
				a fallback function is invoked if none of the fixed keys are found.
				This is handy because you can provide parsed template keys, e.g., <code>foo[bar]</code> and
				<code>foo[baz]</code>, which would be parsed for a type <code>foo</code> that's passed a dynamic value
				<code>bar</code> or <code>baz</code>.
			</div>
			<div>
				<strong>Nota bene</strong>: this required the <a href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_templatex(3)</a> and <a
					href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_templatex_buf(3)</a> functions to have an argument change.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.5</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2017-05-31">2017-05-31</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Clarify documentation for <a href="kcgijson.3.html">kcgijson(3)</a> and add an <code>uninstall</code> rule to
				the GNUmakefile for those not using a package-managed version of the library.
				No code changes.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.6</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2017-08-31">2017-08-31</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Add the <a href="khttp_template.3.html">khttp_template_fd(3)</a> functions for passing a file descriptor into
				the template utility instead of an open file or buffer.
				(Also clean up that documentation.)
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
	<article data-sblg-article="1" data-sblg-tags="version">
		<header>
			<h1>0.9.7</h1>
			<address>Kristaps Dzonsons</address>
			<time datetime="2017-08-31">2017-08-31</time>
		</header>
		<aside>
			<div>
				Fix headers to be more minimal and standards-compliant.
				Add Ross Richardson's <a href="tutorial4.html">Using Pages</a> tutorial.
				Clarify some function elements in <a href="khttp_parse.3.html">khttp_parse(3)</a>.
			</div>
		</aside>
	</article>
</articles>
